HIMESH GANWANI

AI & ML STUDENT

+91-7744924284 🔀 ganwanihk@rknec.edu 🌐 Portfolio 🐚 LinkedIn 📲 GitHub









EDUCATION

• B. Tech in CSE (AI & ML)

Ramdeobaba College Engineering and Management, Nagpur

CGPA-8.9 2020-2024

HSC (12th State Board)

St. Paul School and Jr. College, Nagpur

March 2020 percentage: 88%

10th CBSE Board

Bhavan's B.P Vidya Mandir, Civil Lines, Nagpur

March 2018

percentage: 93.8%

ACHIEVEMENTS AND CERTIFICATES

- Authored and published 3 research papers in reputable journals
- · Secured grant of 2 pantents
- Blockchain Specialization by the University of Buffalo
- Specialization **GANs** bv DeepLearning.Al
- AWS Fundamentals Offered by AWS
- 30 Days of Google Cloud by Google
- Participant at SIH' 22 and SIH'23
- · Achieved 1st rank among collegelevel candidates in the MHTCET examination, securing a remarkable 99.03 percentile
- 8 medals in various Olympiads during schooling

COMPETENCIES

- · Languages Known: English, Hindi, Sindhi, Marathi.
- Quick Learner and a good listener.
- Good Communication Skills in all the languages known.
- · Adaptable and able to pick up new techniques.
- A strong team person having **leadership** qualities.

PROFILE

I see myself as a unique combination of engineering expertise, practical business knowledge, and management skills. I aim to grow personally while creating a substantial impact on the businesses I engage with in the future, thus becoming a valuable asset to society.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

- Programming Languages: Python (Numpy, Pandas, Scikit, Flask), SQL (Oracle 11g), C Language, Java, Javascript, React, HTML5, CSS
- Data Mining and Machine-Learning Algorithms: Classification (SVM, KNN, Random-Forest, Naive-Bayes, Decision Trees), Clustering (K-Means), Neural networks, Regression, Boosting (Adaboost), Supervised and Unsupervised Models.
- Data Structures: Array, Queue, Stack, Tree, Graph, Linked List
- Operating Systems: Windows and Linux (Ubuntu)
- Tools: Visual Studio Code, Jupyter Notebook, Keil5, Oracle 11g, Microsoft Office (Word, Excel, and Powerpoint), CoCalc, AWS, Google Cloud, Tableau
- Open Source: Git, Github

EXPERIENCE

- 1. Completed 10 weeks of Virtual Al-ML Internship offered by AWS and organized by AICTE (MAY 2023 - JULY 2023)
- 2. Member of The CodeBreakers A subsidiary of the Technical Club at RCOEM for 1+ years (DEC 2021 - NOV 2022).
- 3. Part of the Organizing Committee of PRERNA An Anual event organized by NSS RCOEM, for an audience of 1K+ (MARCH 2022)

PROJECTS

1. COLLEGE PREDICTOR, A Machine-Learning-Based Prediction Model built for College Admission [7]

Technology Used: Python Flask, Decision Tree, K-Means

- Research Paper published in IEEE journal
- 2. PROCTOX, A Proficient Exam Monitoring System Using Deep Learning Techniques [7]

Technology Used: Python OpenCV, Caffe Model, Haar-Cascade Frontal Face Detection Model, YOLO Model

- Research Paper published in Springer journal
- 2. DEEPFAKE DETECTION, A machine learning model to identify manipulated or synthesized media

Technology Used: Python OpenCV, Flask, MTCNN, and **EfficientNet models**

Research Paper published in Springer journal